[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
In the regression module, we talked about the relationship between error or
在回归模型里 我们讨论过 误差/正确率
accuracy in the complexity of the model.
和模型复杂度之间的关系
Let's talk a little bit about the relationship in terms of
现在我们来看看
the amount of data you have to learn.
你的模型需要学习多少数据 和模型复杂度之间的关系
And we'll explore the question of how much data we need to learn.
我们会探讨为了学好一个模型 到底需要多少数据
And this is a really difficult and complex question in machine learning.
这在机器学习中 是一个很困难和复杂的问题
So of course, the more data you have, the better,
当然了 在数据质量不错的前提下
as long as the quality of the data is good.
数据总是越多越好
And then bad data, lots of bad data, is much worse to having much less,
坏数据  大量的坏数据
much fewer, data points with really good, clean, high-quality data points.
肯定比拥有少量很好很清晰 高质量的数据 要糟糕得多
Now there's some theoretical techniques to analyze how much data you need.
自然我们可以用一些理论技巧来分析 我们到底需要多少数据
Many of those help you understand kinda the overall trends, but
这些技巧能帮助我们理解数据的总体趋势
really tend to be too loose to use in practice.
但这些技巧对实际应用来说太松散了
In practice, there's some empirical techniques to really try to understand
实际应用中 我们有些很实用的技术
how much error we're making and what that kind of error looks like.
可以帮助我们理解 我们的误差率有多大 以及我们在犯哪种错误
And, in the follow-up courses, we're gonna explore those techniques much further, but
在这系列后面的课程中 我们会更深入探讨这些技术
let me give you a little bit of guidance and
但这里我想给大家一点指导
a little insight on what that can do within the classification side.
一点这些技术在分类领域里的应用指导
Now an important representation for this relationship between data and
在数据和模型质量的关系里 有个很重要的指标
quality is what's called the learning curve.
是我们所谓的 学习曲线
So a learning curve relates the amount of data that we have for
学习曲线把我们有多少数据
training with the error that we're making.
和我们的误差率 联系在一起
And here we're talking about test error.
我们这里说的是测试误差率
Now if you have very little data for training,
如果你的训练数据非常少
then your test error is going to be high.
那么自然测试误差会比较高
But if you have a lot of data for training,
如果你的训练数据比较多
your test error is going to be low.
你的测试误差会比较低
And now, the curve is gonna get better and
所以 随着你拥有越来越多的数据
better as you get more and more and more data.
你的学习曲线会越来越好 (就是测试误差率会越来越低)
Whoops, didn't go through that point, so I'm gonna just erase it.
糟糕 我还没讲到那块呢 那我就删掉这个好了
Now here we go.
我们再接着讲
This is an example learning curve where the quality is getting better as we
图中曲线就是一个学习曲线的例子
add more data.
横轴代表的数据量越来越高的话 纵轴代表的误差率就越来越低
Now you may ask, is there a limit?
那么现在你可能问了  这个曲线趋势有没有个极限呢
Is this quality just going to get better and better forever as you add more data?
如果你一直加入更多的数据 误差率会不会永远地降低下去
Now we know that error's going to decrease as we add more data, the test error.
我们知道 当我们加入更多数据的时候 测试误差会降低
However, there is some gap here.
但是我们看到 误差率的值和零之间有个空隙
And the question is whether that gap can go to zero, and the answer's,
那么问题来了 这个空隙能变成零吗
in general, no.
一般来说 答案是不能
This gap is called the bias.
这个空隙被称作 偏差
So let's discuss a little bit what this bias, or this gap, is.
我们接下来谈谈这个偏差 或说这个空隙 到底是什么
So intuitively,
直觉来说
it says even with infinite data,
偏差代表着 就算你有无限多的数据
the test error will not go to zero.
测试误差也不会变成零
So let's understand why a little bit.
为什么呢
More complex models tend to have less bias.
更复杂的模型一般会有更小的偏差
So if you look at a sentiment analysis classifier that we may building,
所以说如果你看看我们前面建造的情绪分析分类器
if you just use single words like awesome,
如果你只用一些简单的词 好比说 棒 好 很好 可怕 糟糕
good, great, terrible, awful, it can do okay.
分类器也能凑合工作
Maybe it do really well, maybe just does okay.
有可能还工作的挺好的 也有可能就是凑合能用
But even if you have infinite data, even with all the data in the world,
但是就算你有无穷多的数据 你有全世界的数据
you're never gonna get this sentence right, the sushi was not good.
下面这个句子你也分不好类: 这寿司  不(not) 好(good)
Because you're not looking at pairs of words,
原因是你没有考虑 单词对
you're just looking at the words good and not individually.
你仅仅考虑了每个单词本身 比如 好(good)  不(not)
And so more complex models that, for example, deal with combinations of words,
所以有些更复杂的模型 会考虑单词组合
for example, the simply called the bigram model,
举个例子 有所谓 双连词 模型
where you look at pairs of secret words like not good.
这个模型会考虑单词对 比如  不好(not good)
Those models require more parameters, because there's more possibilities.
这类模型需要更多参数 因为有可更多可能
They can do better, they may have a parameter for good, say 1.5.
它们的分类结果可以更好 比如它们给一个单词 "好"(good) 的参数是 1.5
But not good, say -2.1.
但给单词对 "不好"(not good) 的参数是 -2.1
And actually get that sentence, the sushi was not good, correctly.
因此这类模型可以正确把 "这寿司不好" 分类
So they have less bias.
所以它们的偏差会更小
They can represent sentences that couldn't be represented as words, but
它们可以代表那些不能通过单个单词代表的句子
so they're potentially more accurate.
因此它们有可能分类更准确
But they need more data to learn, because there's more parameters.
但这些模型需要更多数据来学习 因为它们参数更多
There's not just a parameter for good, there's now a parameter for not good, and
不仅仅是只有一个对单词 "好" 的参数 它们还有表示 单词对 "不好" 的参数
all possible combinations of words.
以及针对其它各种单词组合的参数
And the more parameters your model has, in general, the more data you need to learn.
一般来说 你的模型参数越多 你学习这个模型所需要的数据也就越多
So let's go back to our example.
我们回头再看我们的例子
We talked about the fact of a amount of training data on the test error.
我们讨论了数据量和误差率之间的关系
So let's say that I'm building a classifier using single words.
比如说我用单个单词来构建一个分类器模型
And the question is, how does that relate to a classifier, based on pairs of words?
它和一个在用单词对的基础上构建的分类器 比较起来怎么样呢
Now for a classifier based on bigrams, when you have less data,
如果你只有比较少的数据 一个用双连词构建的分类器
it's not going to do as well because it has more parameters to fit.
表现不会怎么样的 因为它需要拟合更多参数
But when you have more data, it's going to do better because it's going to be able to
但一旦你有了更多的数据 这个模型成绩就会更好
capture settings like, the sushi was not good.
因为它可以正确分类  类似 "这寿司不好" 这样的句子
And so the behavior you're gonna get is something like this.
所以说学习曲线看起来会像这样:
And at some point, there's a crossover where it starts doing better than
在某个点 这两种模型的误差率会交叉
the classifier with single words.
就是随着数据变多 双连词模型开始比 独个单词模型 结果更好
But notice the background model still has some bias here.
但请注意双连词模型依然还是有些偏差
Although the bias is smaller, it still has some bias.
这偏差比独个单词模型变小了  但依然存在
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community